Guide to the Joseph Urban Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: New York
  - Subseries III.7: Architecture and Design, 1914-1933
    - Kaufmann Department Store, Proposed, Pittsburgh, Pa., July 23, 1928:
      - --First Floor Plan, 47x49 (38x41) cm. (Box D10, Folder 8)
      - --Mezzanine Floor Plan, 47x49 (38x41) cm. (Box D10, Folder 9)
      - --Special Counters, 47x49 (31x32) cm. (Box D10, Folder 10)
      - --Counters, grill detail, 47x49 (25x28) cm. (Box D10, Folder 11)
      - --First Floor detail, 29x30 (25x27) cm. (Box D11, Folder 1)
      - --First Floor Ceiling Plan, 29x30 (25x27) cm. (Box D11, Folder 2)
      - --Ground plan of beauty Salon, Scott and Teegen (Box D11, Folder 3)
    - Bossert Hotel, Grill Room, Brooklyn, 1928:
      - 3 watercolor drawings of screen & plans, 33x59 cm., 2 sig. (Box D11, Folder 4)
      - 13 technical drawings, detail (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - 3 technical drawings & prints (Box 14-9-10, Folder 2)
      - 9 photographs (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Bedell Department Store, New York City, August 6, 1928:
      - 2 drawings, pencil, sig.:
      - --34th Street elevation, 48x48 (26x26) cm. (Box D11, Folder 5)
      - --Section, Rotunda, Exhibition Hall, 48x48 (21x21) cm. (Box D12, Folder 1)
      - 5 drawings, watercolor, August 6, 1928, sig.:
      - --perspective of 34th St. elevation, 48x49 (20x20) cm. (Box D12, Folder 2)
      - --show window, 48x49 (20x20) cm. (Box D12, Folder 3)
      - --Show room, 48x49 (20x20) cm. (Box D12, Folder 4)
      - --Millinery Department, 48x48 (20x20) cm. (Box D12, Folder 5)
      - --elevator, 28x31 (23x20) cm. (Box B28, Folder 3)
      - 1 watercolor sketch of Millinery Department (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - 5 photographs of design (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - 9 photographs of store (Box A10, Folder 13)
      - 7 photographs of Store (Box C19, Folder 9)
      - Architectural Forum, 2 p. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - William Penn Hotel, Pittsburgh, August 1928, 1932:
      The opening for the renovated hotel was held in May of 1929. The Chatterbox Room was commissioned in 1932.
      - 6 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Tea Room detail and plan, 51x43 cm., sig. (Box D13, Folder 1)
      - --Exhibition Room, 51x43 (33x34) cm., sig. (Box D13, Folder 2)
      - --Men's Lounge, 51x43 cm., sig. (Box D13, Folder 3)
      - --Ballroom, 34x51 (25x45) cm., sig. (Box D13, Folder 4)
      - --Ballroom Ceiling Decoration, 37x50 (30x41) cm. (Box D13, Folder 5)
      - --Wall Panel, 46x19 (18x12) cm. (Box C19, Folder 10)
      - --2 Wall panels, Chatterbox Room, 20x68 cm. (Box E120)
      - Hotel magazine cover, 5/29 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - 3 photos of Chatterbox Room (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - New Amsterdam Roof, 1928:
      Urban redesigned the New Amsterdam roof garden for Ziegfeld's final Midnight Frolic which opened December 29, 1928.
      - (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - 2 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --Butterfly-floral pattern, yellow, 26x32 (15x32) cm. (Box B31, Folder 9)
      - --section: elephant panel, 37x16 (27x11) cm. (Box B31, Folder 10)
      - 5 technical drawings (Box 14-9-10, Folder 3)
    - International Magazine Building, 1928-1929:
      - 6 photographs (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - 8 photographs and one etching (Box C20, Folder 1)
    - Encyclopaedia Britannica article, 1928-1929
      - Article on Steele MacKaye, 9 p. (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Letter from Percy MacKaye, ts., 4 p. (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Hutton Ball, 1928
      - 3 drawings, watercolor and pencil on board:
      - --A: Mountain background, 29x38 (23x33) cm. (Box B31, Folder 11)
      - --B: Mountain with floral foreground, 36x42 (24x30) cm. (Box C19, Folder 11)
      - --C: Chinese lanterns, 33x42 (20x29) cm. (Box B31, Folder 12)
    - American Designers' Gallery, 1928-1929:
      Urban joined with other artists to establish a cooperative art gallery at 145 W. 57th St. Their first exhibit was shown in October of 1928 for which Urban designed a young lady's room entitled "Repose."
      - 14 photographs (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - 7 letters, ts., 10 p. (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Central Park Casino, 1929:
      - 3 drawings, watercolor:
      - --external view, 26x36 (14x24) cm., sig. (Box B28, Folder 4)
      - --Ceiling pattern, 34x53 (30x45) cm. (Box D13, Folder 6)
      - --North and South Wall, Ballroom, 28x63 cm. (Box 14-9-1, Folder B.6)
      - 2 detail drawings and letter (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - 9 technical drawings (Box 14-9-10, Folder 4)
      - 26 photographs (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - 10 photographs (Box B28, Folder 5)
      - 16 photographs, Sigurd Fischer (Box C20, Folder 2)
      - 2 articles from Architectural Record, 32 p. (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art 11th annual exhibition of American Industrial Art, February and March 1929:
      - 16 photographs of sun porch and man's den (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - American Architect reprint, 9 p. (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Mosaic Messenger cover (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Woman's Journal, 3 p. (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Emerich Residence, Chicago, Il., interior design, 1929:
      Remodeling of the home of Banker Melvin L. Emerich of Chicago.
      - 2 photographs of interiors (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Hartman Trunks, 1929
      - 2 drawings and 1 photostat of patterns (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Jewish Art Theater, proposed, 1929:
      - 4 photostats of plans (Box 31, Folder 19)
      - 19 photostats of plans (Box D13, Folder 7)
      - 8 plans (Box D13, D14)
      - 2 photographs of proscenium (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Cadillac magazine advertisement, 1929:
      - 6 ad sketches (Box 31, Folder 20)
      - 1 letter, McManus Inc, ts (Box 31, Folder 20)
      - 7 sketches and ads (Box B28, Folder 6)
    - Gingerbread House, 1929:
      F. H. Bennett of Wheatsworth, Inc. asked Urban to make the Gingerbread House after seeing the Urban-designed Metropolitan production of Hänsel and Gretel.
      - 18 photographs of building (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - 1 tearsheet, Fortune, p 89 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Postcard, letter and ceramics catalog (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Theatres, 1929:
      - 10 prints of ground plans (Box 14-9-10, Folder 5)
      - 3 Music Center ground plans, photostats, 40x28 cm. (Box 14-9-10, Folder 5)
      - 2 Reinhardt Theater ground plans (Box E121, E122)
      - Mock up of p. 35, Music Center Site (Box B28, Folder 7)
      - Detail of plastic relief, p. 48 (Box B28, Folder 7)
      - 5 Music Center plans (Box E123-E127)
      - 5 Music Center plans, photostats (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - 47 loose pages (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Book (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - New School for Social Research, 1929-1931:
      - 19 drawings, watercolor and/or pencil:
      - --Talk over corner perspective, 32x41(15x22) cm. (Box B28, Folder 8)
      - --Talk-over niches, 36x30 (22x19) cm. (Box B28, Folder 9)
      - --Classroom, 30x45 (13x28) cm. (Box B28, Folder 10)
      - --12th Street Front, 1929, 46x32 (33x19) cm. (Box C20, Folder 3)
      - --Main Lobby Color Treatment, 37x37 (26x26) cm. (Box C20, Folder 4)
      - --Classroom perspective, 32x41 (19x31) cm. (Box C21, Folder 1)
      - --Auditorium perspective, 32x41 (20x31) cm. (Box C21, Folder 2)
      - --Street elevation, 38x52 (25x34) cm. (Box D14, Folder 7)
      - --Basement Lobby Color Treatment, 37x50 (24x40) cm. (Box D14, Folder 8)
      - --Reception Room Color Treatment, 37x50 (19x42) cm. (Box D15, Folder 1)
      - --Faculty Dining Room Color Treatment, 37x52 (19x40) cm. (Box D15, Folder 2)
      - --Faculty Dining Room Color Treatment, Green, 37x50 (19x40) cm. (Box D15, Folder 3)
      - --Director's offices, 36x50 (20x41) cm. (Box D15, Folder 4)
      - --Assistant Director's offices, 37x53 (19x41) cm. (Box D15, Folder 5)
      - --Ground plan, classrooms, 37x51 (25x33) cm. (Box D16, Folder 1)
      - --Dance Studio Color Treatment, 37x67 (19x56) cm. (Box 14-10-1, Folder A.1)
      - --2 Street elevation Color Treatment, 47x67 cm. (Box E128-E129)
      - 13 ground plans (Box B29-B30)
      - Main floor ground plan (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Letters and notes, 6 p. (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Book of Color Control Patches (Box A10, Folder 14)
      - Ordynski correspondence, 11 p. (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - 10 photographs (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - 30 photographs, interior & exterior (Box A10, Folder 15-44)
      - 4 photographs, interiors (Box C21, Folder 3)
      - 5 flyers, pamphlets, forms (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - 2 articles, Architectural Digest, 14 p. (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Architectural Record, 13 p. (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - 2 booklets (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - 1 chapter from Johnson's autobiography, 18 p. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Atlantic Beach Club, Long Island, NY, 1930-1931:
      Urban also designed Café de Paris for Night on the Riviera fete held August 3, 1930.
      - 13 drawings, watercolor, pencil and ink:
      - --Main entrance Terrace Apartments, 33x34 (17x19) cm., sig. (Box B30, Folder 6)
      - --Isometric view of Terraced Apts., 47x51 (40x44) cm., sig. (Box D16, Folder 2)
      - --Beach front view, blue background, 57x74 (40x44) cm. (Box E130)
      - --Beach front, green, 51x76 (42x72) cm. (Box E131)
      - --Room, color isometric drawing, 56x76 (43x36) cm. (Box E132)
      - --Apartment perspective and floor plan, 76x51 (60x39) cm., sig. (Box E133)
      - --Detail of End bays, 51x76 (38x55) cm. (Box E134)
      - --Alternate floor plan, 51x76 (35x60) cm. (Box E135)
      - --Typical floor plan, 51x76 (42x72) cm., sig. (Box E136)
      - --Basement ground plan, 51x76 (43x72) cm., sig. (Box E137)
      - --First floor ground plan, 51x76 (43x72) cm., sig. (Box E138)
      - --5th and 6th floor plan, 51x76 (43x72) cm., sig. (Box E139)
      - --Penthouse floor plan, 51x76 (43x72) cm., sig. (Box E140)
      - 11 photographs (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Photograph of Café de Paris, August 1930 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - 18 photographs (Box A15, Folder 1)
      - 10 photographs (Box C21, C22)
    - Suburban Movie Theater, 1931:
      Westchester County, NY
      - Interior, facing screen, pastel, 21x55 (16x50) cm. (Box D16, Folder 3)
      - Plan, longitudinal section, 46x75 (26x63) cm. (Box E141)
      - 4 photographs of model (Box B30, Folder 7)
      - 3 photographs of model (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - 2 articles, 6 p. (Box 32, Folder 6)
        [See also Architectural League Exhibition, 1932-1933]
    - Park Avenue Restaurant, 1931:
      - 4 photographs of club interior (Box C22, Folder 3)
      - 2 Architectural Forum reprints, 8 p. ea. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Palace of the Soviets, 1931:
      The Russian Government held an open competition to find an architect for their assembly hall. Urban was one of six prominent architects chosen to present a design for the building for $10,000.
      - 130 p. reports, specs (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - 79 p. correspondence (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - 2 booklets, Russian (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Map of Moscow (Box A15, Folder 2)
      - 7 drawings, watercolor, pencil and ink:
      - --Assembly Hall, 36x46 (33x41) cm. (Box D17, Folder 1)
      - --Colonnade, 34x55 (27x41) cm. (Box D17, Folder 2)
      - --Perspective Central Plaza, 34x46 cm. (Box D17, Folder 3)
      - --Interior, Large Hall with demonstration, 74x64 (70x61) cm. (Box 14-10-2, Folder 5)
      - --Ground plan, 47x60 (39x54) cm. (Box 14-10-1, Folder B.1)
      - --Ground plan with landscaping, 43x57 cm. (Box 14-10-1, Folder B.2)
      - --Perspective of large hall, 46x63 cm. (Box 14-10-1, Folder B.7)
      - 10 plans (Box D18, Folder 1-10)
      - 31 photographs (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - 5 photographs (Box A15, Folder 2)
    - Lerner, Max Suburban House, 1932:
      - Photograph of model, back view (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Photograph of model, side view (Box A15, Folder 3)
    - Architectural League One-Man Show, February 1932:
      Joseph Urban donated proceeds for the benefit of New York's unemployed draftsmen.
      - 5 photographs of Joseph Urban's office (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - Plan for small house, awarded 4th prize (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Fairy Tale book illustration reprints, April 22, 1932:
      The Yonkers Statesman reported on April 22, 1932 that an exhibit of prints from 24 fairy tale illustrations was held at a Yonkers book shop on 155 North Broadway.
      - 34 reprints of illustrations with index (Box A15, Folder 4 & 5)
      - 5 reprints of illustrations with index (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - 9 photographs of illustrations (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Congress Hotel, Joseph Urban Room, Chicago, Illinois, 1932:
      - 2 drawings, watercolor:
      - --Urban Room, 41x41 (29x25) cm. (Box D17, Folder 4)
      - --Pattern, 23x23 (18x18) cm. (Box B30, Folder 8)
      - Print of Joseph Urban Room (Box D17, Folder 4)
      - Blueprint of Balloon Room (Box 14-9-10, Folder 6)
      - 2 photographs (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Photograph (Box A15, Folder 6)
      - Photograph, mounted (Box D17, Folder 4)
    - Urban, Harrison and Hood Houses Co-design, 1932:
      Raymond Hood, Joseph Urban, and Wallace K. Harrison jointly proposed a plan for houses constructed largely of steel for mass production.
      - Two drawings watercolor:
      - --Neighborhood, 43x52 (22x40) cm. (Box D17, Folder 5)
      - --Houses, front elevations (Box D17, Folder 6)
      - Ground plan for house (Box D17, Folder 6)
    - Book-Cadillac Hotel, Mayfair Room, Detroit, Michigan, 1932:
      - 6 sketches (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - 15 detail sketches (Box 14-9-10, Folder 7)
      - 2 photographs (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Architectural League Exhibition, 1932-1933:
      Urban arranged the 48th Annual Exhibition of the Architectural League of New York, held from February 18 to March 12, 1933, at the Galleries of the American Fine Arts Society. Urban received the President's Medal for "the unique architectural treatment of the galleries and the effective installation of the exhibits" and a Medal of Honor for his set model for the unproduced religious pageant Light
      - Letters, lists, plans, 84 p. (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - 4 technical drawings (Box 14-9-1, Folder B.8)
      - 11 photographs of exhibit and award ceremony (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - 2 photographs of exhibit (Box C22, Folder 4)
      - 2 certificates of award (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Exhibit catalog (Box A15, Folder 7)
      - Architecture, 2 p (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Medal with case (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Chicago World's Fair: Century of Progress, opened May 7, 1933:
      Urban was the director of Light for the fair and designed panels for the New York exhibit. He also proposed a stage design for a religious pageant The Light which was never produced.
      - 1 letter from Raymond Hood, ms. (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - 1 blueprint of New York State Exhibit (Box 14-9-10, Folder 8)
      - Reference picture for NY State Exhibit (Box A15, Folder 8)
      - 17 drawings, watercolor and pencil:
      - --11 panels of buildings, 33x84 cm. (Box E142-E146)
      - --Agricultural Building, 63x41 cm. (Box E147)
      - --Fountain of metal, 34x61 cm. (Box 14-10-1, Folder A.2)
      - --Esplanade of flags, 42x58 cm. (Box 14-10-1, Folder A.3)
      - --Buildings in blue, yellow, 44x70 (41x67) cm. (Box 14-10-1, Folder B.3)
      - --Orange building with radiator center, 34x59 (26x46) cm. (Box 14-9-1, Folder B.9)
      - --Green building with gray circle, 48x64 (45x58) cm. (Box 14-9-1, Folder B9)
      - 1 booklet, Light Recommendations (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - 2 newspaper magazine pullout sections (Box B30, Folder 9)
      - 6 programs (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Katherine Brush Apartment, 1933:
      - (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - 3 photographs (Box B30, Folder 10)
      - Article, House & Garden, January 1933 (Box A15, Folder 9)
    - Undated:
      - Decorative Illustrations, (5 drawings, 24x22 cm., sig.) (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Hearst House:
      - (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - 1 ground plan, blueprint of room (Box 14-9-10, Folder 9)
    - Huron Building, Detroit:
      - (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Blueprint, ceiling plan (Box 14-9-10, Folder 10)
    - Knickerbocker Hotel:
      - (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - 2 blueprints (Box 14-9-10, Folder 11)
    - Mallin Furniture Company:
      - (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - Furniture designs, notebook (Box A15, Folder A)
    - Pennsylvania Hotel roof garden:
      - Photograph of roof garden (Box 33, Folder 14)
- Series IV. Biographical
  - Subseries IV.1: Joseph Urban
    - Letters, mementos, 1917-1930 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - 2 certificates as NY architect, 1925, 1931 (Box C22, Folder 5)
    - 5 caricatures, 1896-1920s (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - 17 photographs of Urban, 1912-1933 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - 5 photographs of Urban and office, 1932-1933 (Box A15, Folder 10)
    - 6 photographs of studio artists (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - 22 photographs, family and friends, 1915-1960s (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Drawing, Charles Williams[?] (Box A15, Folder 11)
    - 36 articles, 1914-1981 (Box 34, Folder 3 & 4)
    - 2 files biographical material (Box 34, Folder 5 & 6)
- Series V. Other Donations
  - Subseries V.1 Gretl Urban
    - Mementos (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Biographical files (Box 35, Folder 1 & 2)
    - 24 family photographs, 1903-1932 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1988 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Subseries V.2: Cole, Robert & Randolph Carter [Urban biographers]
    - Biographical notes (Box 35 & 36)
    - Letters from Gretl Urban, 1980-1991 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Photographs for Urban biography (Box 36 & 37)
    - 24 Audiocassettes of Carter and Cole interviews with Gretl (Box 39)
  - Subseries V.3: Urban, Mary, 1928-1966
    - Biographical notes (Box 37, Folder 3-8)
    - Douggie [Donald M. Douglass] biography (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - 9 photographs of Urban rooms (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Urban Assoc., 1921-1937 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Guest lists, 1934-1946 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Exhibits, 1959-1966 (Box 38, Folder 5-8)
    - 65 Slides of Mary Urban's paintings, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Banks, 1962-1964 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Wages, domestic staff, 1964-1966 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Reel to reel tape of Mary reading articles on Urban (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Subseries V.4: Other Donations
    - (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Japanese Calendar, 1994 (Box 14-9-1, Folder B.10)
    - Video of Show Boat Documentary, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Exhibit blowups, Museum of City of New York (Box 39, Folder 6)
- Series VI: Set Models
  - Aegyptische Helena [Egyptian Helen]
    - Act I, Met, 11/6/28, (2 boxes)
      [Rehoused 2000]
  - Aegyptische Helena [Egyptian Helen]
    - Act II: Tent, Met, 11/6/28, (3 boxes)
      [Rehoused 2000. One box includes part of Fidelio]
  - Annie Dear [Annabella]
    - Rainbow Garden, Ziegfeld, 11/4/24, (1 box)
      [Rehoused 2000. Shares box with Golden Dawn]
  - Annie Dear [Annabella]
    - Kitchen Garden Cyclorama, Ziegfeld, 11/4/24, (1 boxes)
  - Antonia
    - Act II Cabaret Scene 1925, Theater, 10/20/25, (1 bundle)
      [Rehoused 2000. Not a set model.]
  - Apple Blossoms
    - Act I: School Garden, Theater, 10/7/19, (2 boxes)
  - Bath and Tennis Club
    - Persian ballroom, Architecture and Design, July 1926, (2 boxes)
      [Rehoused 2000. Model formerly cataloged under Elektra]
  - Behold Thy Wife
    - Act III: Library, Theater, 1915, (2 boxes)
      [Renovated for exhibit 2000]
  - Betsy
    - Garden Scene, Ziegfeld, 12/28/26, (1 box)
  - Boccaccio
    - Act I: City Square, Met, 1/2/31, (3 boxes)
  - Boccaccio
    - Act I: City Square Backdrop, Met, 1/2/31, (1 box)
  - Boccaccio
    - Act 2: Cooper's, Met, 1/2/31, (3 boxes)
  - Boccaccio
    - Act 3: Park, Met, 1/2/31, (1 box)
  - Buried Treasure
    - Unknown, Film, 1922, (2 boxes)
  - Cosi Fan Tutti
    - Portal, Met, 3/4/22, (1 box)
  - Don Carlos
    - Act II, 2: Outside of Convent, Met, 12/23/20, (1 box)
  - Don Giovanni
    - Convent Scene[?] -- Garden Scene -- Village and Harbor Scene[?] -- Ballroom Scene -- Arched Courtyard -- one unidentified scene, Met, 11/29/29
      [One scene rehoused. Original housing: cartons 5-8.]
  - Don Giovanni
    - Act I, sc 5: Ballroom Scene, Met, Met 11/29/29, (1 carton)
      [Renovated for exhibit, 2000. One scene rehoused.]
  - Donna Juanita
    - Act I: Patio, Met, 1/2/32, (1 box)
  - Dutchess of Elba
    - Act I: 2 decks, Theater, 1925/26, (1 box)
  - Dutchess of Elba
    - Act I: Outside farmhouse, Theater, 1925/26, (1 box)
  - Dutchess of Elba
    - Act I: Store Room [not used], Theater, 1925/26, (1 box)
  - Dutchess of Elba
    - Act II: Sitting Room, Theater, 1925/26, (1 box)
  - Dutchess of Elba
    - Act II & III: decks, Theater, 1925/26, (1 box)
  - Dutchess of Elba
    - Act III: bedroom, Theater, 1925/26, (1 box)
  - Elektra
    - Persian Ball, Met, 12/3/32, ()
      [Untouched. Some confusion with Bath & Tennis Club. Carton 22]
  - Fidelio
    - Act I, Sc 1, Met, 1/22/27, (3 boxes)
  - Fidelio
    - Act I, Sc 2, Met, 1/22/27, (2 boxes)
  - Fidelio
    - Act II, Sc 1, Met, 1/22/27, (3 boxes)
  - Fidelio
    - Act II Sc 2, Met, 1/22/27, (2 boxes*)
      [Rehoused 2000. *Plus one box shelved with Aegyptische Helena]
  - Flying High
    - In Front of Apartment -- In Front of Major Watts' Apt. -- Field at Night Sc. -- Flight Sc. [?] -- 3 Curtain -- Flying Field Sc., Theater, 3/3/30
      [One scene rehoused. Original Housing: 5 bundles plus cartons 19 & 20.]
  - Flying High
    - Act 2.6: flight, Theater, 3/3/30, (1 box)
      [Renovated for exhibit, 2000]
  - Fra Gherado
    - Act I Sc 2 -- Act II Court Yard -- Act III Interior -- Act III Sc 2 City Plaza, Met, 3/21/29
      [Untouched. [Out 8/2/00]. Original houring: 4 bundles plus carton 12.]
  - Freischutz
    - Unknown/ 3 models, Met, 3/22/24
      [Untouched. Original houring: two bundles plus one oversize bundle]
  - George White Scandals
    - Portals -- Observatory Scene -- Cherry Girls Drop -- Heaven Scene -- Cotton Field Scene -- Sunrise Scene -- Editors Office -- Mission Scene -- Mine Scene -- Sunrise Scene(not used) -- Misc. parts -- Locomotive Scene -- Wonder Bar Scene -- Peanut Vendor -- Street Scene -- Garden Scene -- Green and Red Dome Scene (not used) -- Tent Scene -- Microphone Scene (not used) -- Portals - Portal WIng - Silver Wings -- Empire State Bldg. Scene -- Charriot Scene -- Dream Scene -- Spring Scene -- Doctor's Office Scene -- Observatory Scene (not used) -- Ray Scene -- Heaven Scene (not used) -- Paradise Scene (not used) -- Good Old Days Scene, Theater, 9/14/31
      [Untouched. Original houring: 30 bundles]
  - Golden Dawn
    - Act I Sc 3: Cut drop, Theater, 11/30/27, (1 box*)
      [Rehoused 2000. *shares box with Annie Dear]
  - Golden Dawn
    - Act I. Sc 3, Theater, 11/30/27, (2 boxes)
      [Rehoused 2000. cartons 24-28 [Cartons might be "Human Nature"]]
  - Golden Dawn
    - Act II Sc 2, Theater, 11/30/27, (3 boxes)
      [Rehoused 2000. Cartons might be "Human Nature"]
  - Good Fairy
    - Lawyer's Office, Theater, 11/24/31, (1 box)
      [Rehoused 2000. There was apparently some Palace of the Soviets (Arch.) material included in the bundles and removed.]
  - Good Fairy
    - I: Chamber, Scene B, Theater, 11/24/31, (2 boxes)
  - Greatest Nation
    - Unknown, Theater, 2/28/16, (1 bundle)
      [Untouched]
  - Hansel and Gretel
    - Unknown, Met, 11/5/27, (1 oversize bundle)
  - Hot - Cha! [Laid in Mexico]
    - Nightclub -- Outside of Arena -- Fiesta Portal -- Wall of Arena -- Training Wuarters -- 1 Tree Border; 1 leg Drop; 1 Canopy -- Public Square -- Parlk Scene -- Train Scene -- Girls Room -- Procession -- Cafe -- Street Scene --, Ziegfeld, 3/8/32, (13 bundles)
  - Human Nature [Gun Powder]
    - Act I, Theater, 11/30/27, (2 boxes)
      [Rehoused 2000. Cartons 24-28? [Cartons might be Golden Dawn]]
  - Jonny Spielt Auf